A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Secretary of Labor, 2018-2021
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Virginia Secretary of Labor, 2018-2021
The Library of Virginia
53526
.70 cu. ft. (2 boxes)
Virginia. Secretary of Labor.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred on 14 January 2022 by the Office of the Secretary of Labor, 1111 East Broad Street, Richmond, Virginia, 23219.
Biographical Information
Megan Healy was appointed the first Secretary of Labor by Governor Ralph Northam in 1 July 2021 and served until 15 January 2022. Previously she had served as Chief Workforce Development Advisor to Governor Northam. The Secretary of Labor was created by legislation (HB 2321) passed during the General Assembly's 2021 Special Session. The legislation transferred from the Secretary of Commerce and Trade to the Secretary of Labor responsibility for the Department of Labor and Industry, the Department of Professional and Occupational Regulation, and the Virginia Employment Commission. HB 2321 also removed the position of Chief Workforce Development Advisor and reassigned its duties to the Secretary of Labor.
Scope and Content
Records, 2018-2021, created and maintained by Megan Healy, Chief Workforce Development Advisor (2018-2021) and Secretary of Labor (2021-2022), during the administration of Governor Ralph Northam (2018-2022). The records include bills, correspondence, memorandum, reports, and other working papers.
The bulk of the records are Governor decision requests (gold sheets), 2018-2021, regarding a variety of topics from attending conferences, to nominations for boards, approval of reports, and requests for letters. Of note are reports including the State workforce recovery plan (Rev it up!), Virginia's Combined Workforce State plan for the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (WIOA), Virginia Career Works public emergency health plans, and a report for the Task force on Misclassification and Payroll fraud.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
Contents List
- Build Virginia Advisory Board, 2019 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 2021 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Future of Work - Virginia Taskforce Report, 2021 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Governor Decision Requests, 2018 January-September (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Governor Decision Requests, 2018 September-December (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Governor Decision Requests, 2019 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Governor Decision Requests, 2020 March-September (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Governor Decision Requests, 2020 September-December (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Governor Decision Requests, 2021 February-July (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Governor Decision Requests, 2021 October-December (Box 2, Folder 1)
- High demand occupations list, 2021 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Re-employing Virginians (Rev-It-Up!), 2020 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Taskforce on misclassification and payroll fraud, 2018-2019 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Virginia Board of Workforce Development, 2020-2021 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Virginia Career Works, 2020 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Virginia Combined State Plan (PYS 2020-2023), 2020 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)